# Tim Huitt

Broomfield, CO 80021 | 914-960-1960 timhuitt@gmail.com | github.com/timhuitt | timhuitt.com

#### FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

As an experienced Software Developer with a blend of self-taught expertise and formal education, I have been responsible for the professional development and deployment of multiple python and VBA applications, in addition to many personal and collaborative projects. I excel in leadership, team collaboration, and process optimization. My past experiences and commitment to continuous growth positions me as a valuable asset in delivering high-quality software solutions.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: Python, JavaScript, Java, VBA, HTML, CSS, SQL

Libraries and Frameworks: React, Express.js, Node.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Mongoose Databases and other: PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB, JSON, EJS, JSX, REST, MVC, MTV, API, Git, npm Interpersonal: Leadership, Team Guidance, Training, Project Coordination, Client Communication, Relationship Building, Management, Process Efficiency, Communication Skills, Problem-Solving, Self-Motivation, Adaptability

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

### Auto Component - GitHub | npm | auto-component.com - React, OpenAI, Express, Node, Javascript

AI driven code generation for streamlined UI element creation enabled through integrated prompt entry

- ❖ Engineered base AI prompt for the translation of user prompts and the delivery of consistent JSX code structures
- Designed and built core React component with drag and drop functionality for seamless integration with any project
- ❖ Implemented the use of 3rd party components for enhanced user experience and real-time rendering

### Green Diary - GitHub | App - Django, PostgreSQL, Python, Bootstrap, API

CO2 tracking platform that helps you monitor the environmental impact of your vehicle trips

- ❖ Conceptualized and built the Frontend UI with HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap to create a user-friendly interface
- Devised backend solutions using Django and PostgreSQL for efficient data handling and seamless integration
- ❖ Incorporated a specialized API to provide accurate carbon emission estimates, enhancing the app's core functionality

### Pawzbe - GitHub | pawzbe.com - Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node, JavaScript, EJS, Bootstrap, API

Social media app for your pet to share photos and stories, comment and like others' posts, and explore other pet profiles

- ❖ Collaborated with two teammates to create a full CRUD application with a dynamic and easy to use interface
- ❖ Integrated OAuth for user authentication and Bootstrap for responsive design and intuitive user experience
- ❖ Employed RESTful routing and MVC architecture guidelines to ensure organized structure and project scalability

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Denver Data Analytics - Project Coordinator / Software Developer**

Denver, CO, 02/2021 - 08/2023

- Designed, developed, and deployed multiple python/VBA applications, providing greater data/processing efficiency
- Worked with and managed a small group to collect and compile analytical data for private and municipal clients
- Deployed, operated, maintained, and oversaw the use of data collection equipment

#### **Lightshade - Assistant Manager**

Federal Heights, CO, 03/2019 - 01/2021

- Built multiple Excel applications used by management to reduce time spent on redundant tasks
- ❖ Managed a retail establishment with 30+ employees and up to \$100,000/day in sales
- Directed and oversaw the operations, including cash/employee management, inventory/ordering, scheduling

## Merrill Lynch - Senior Financial Advisor

Ridgefield, CT. 08/2012 - 02/2018

- Created Excel applications to assist with managing client information, bookkeeping, and record keeping
- ♦ Managed investment portfolios, retirement and education accounts, insurance, and mortgages, for 30+ affluent clients
- ❖ Worked as a team of 4 advisors with over 200 clients and \$500M in managed assets

### **EDUCATION**

**General Assembly, Software Engineering** 

Remote, Certificate Expected: 01/2024

Fullsail University, Computer Animation, Bachelor of Arts

Winter Park, FL, Degree Received 12/2011